<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Marco Franzon on KubeTips</title>
    <link>https://kubetips.cloud/authors/marco-franzon/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Marco Franzon on KubeTips</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://kubetips.cloud/twitter-shared-link.png</url>
      <link>https://kubetips.cloud/twitter-shared-link.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 23:40:55 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kubetips.cloud/authors/marco-franzon/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Find processes in docker containers: quick tip to avoid bad surprises </title>
      <link>https://kubetips.cloud/posts/dockertoprocess/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 23:40:55 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kubetips.cloud/posts/dockertoprocess/</guid>
      <description>Containerization is cool, but sometimes it can hide unwanted guests. Keep track of all the running processes, gives you the certainty that everything is running correctly </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker and GPUs: quick start to deploy your next project, without pain configurations</title>
      <link>https://kubetips.cloud/posts/dockergpu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2022 23:40:55 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kubetips.cloud/posts/dockergpu/</guid>
      <description>Docker and GPU are your final combination to scale your projects. Let&amp;#39;s see how to configure the environment and the the requirements to be ready in few steps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create your Docker image in one minute. Just do it!</title>
      <link>https://kubetips.cloud/posts/dockerimage/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 23:40:55 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kubetips.cloud/posts/dockerimage/</guid>
      <description>Docker is the most used engine to run our containers. Very often it is the backend of a Kubernetes deployment so, it is necessary know it very well to administer properly a k8s cluster</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes actions to modify deployed resources. Sneaky changes to avoid your boss&#39; anger! </title>
      <link>https://kubetips.cloud/posts/kubemodifyres/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 01:09:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kubetips.cloud/posts/kubemodifyres/</guid>
      <description>There are several ways to modify deployed resources in Kubernetes. Here a brief summary on the different methods you can use and some suggestions on why choose one or the other in different situations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PersistenVolume: choose the correct policy to avoid bad surprises. Don&#39;t lose your data!</title>
      <link>https://kubetips.cloud/posts/pvpolicies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 23:41:44 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kubetips.cloud/posts/pvpolicies/</guid>
      <description>PersistenVolume (PV) is a Kubernetes resource, that gives you the possibility to obtain storage from the infrastructure without worry about the storage technologies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using a git repository as volume for a Pod</title>
      <link>https://kubetips.cloud/posts/gitsidecar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 23:26:58 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kubetips.cloud/posts/gitsidecar/</guid>
      <description>Volumes in Kubernetes could be initialised with several types.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NetworkPolicy : Enabling network isolation between Pods in the same Namespace</title>
      <link>https://kubetips.cloud/posts/isolatedns/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 14:54:19 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kubetips.cloud/posts/isolatedns/</guid>
      <description>Pods are, by default, able to connect each other</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make the right choice: one or more Containers in a Pod ?</title>
      <link>https://kubetips.cloud/posts/containersinpod/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 23:40:55 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kubetips.cloud/posts/containersinpod/</guid>
      <description>During the design phase you have to make a lot of right choices to avoid bad surprises during the deploy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes in Cloud: easy way to deploy an EKS cluster (AWS)</title>
      <link>https://kubetips.cloud/posts/k8scloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 20:24:02 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kubetips.cloud/posts/k8scloud/</guid>
      <description>One of the most used service, to have your Kubernetes cluster deploy in cloud, is the Elastic Kubernetes Service provided by AWS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes: solutions to deploy it locally</title>
      <link>https://kubetips.cloud/posts/selfhostedk8s/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2022 11:11:21 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kubetips.cloud/posts/selfhostedk8s/</guid>
      <description>In this article I want to summarize the most used softwares to deploy a local Kubernetes cluster on your local machine. Having a local deployment of your infrastructure is always a good idea for testing and debugging. There are several platforms you can choose to quickly have your self-hosted Kubernetes.
Minikube Minikube is probably the most used choice. It can runs in all the major OS and offers an easy installation guide.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
